From now on, auto mode will be the
default in CloudCode. But, what is auto
mode and why you should even care? But
first, we need the right context. In
CloudCode, we have six permission modes.
Permission mode is a setting in
CloudCode that controls how much it asks
you before doing anything. Before the
recent change, the default was manual
approval. The new default is auto mode
and it does almost everything. It uses
something called AI classifier that
we're going to dive into in a second and
it aims to block dangerous actions. If
you want to switch between permissions
while you use CloudCode, you can use the
shift tab. You can see that I'm using
the manual mode. I can switch to accept
edits mode, plan mode, and auto mode.
There are two more permissions modes
that you are not able to change while
CloudCode is running. The first one is
don't ask. With this mode, you can
execute only pre-approved actions and
everything else is auto denied. So, if
you have a strong list of allowed
permissions, it can work for you. The
second mode is very popular, which is
bypass permission. It skips all the
checks and allows CloudCode to do
everything it wants, fetch the web, edit
files, execute bash commands, and so on.
Unlike other YouTube channels, I don't
recommend to use this option. You need
to have control over the agent. But
before we continue, I want to talk about
the difference between auto mode, accept
edits, and bypass permissions. Well,
bypass permissions gives the agent
everything it wants to execute.
every command immediately without asking
for our approval. With the accept edits,
we give it permission to edit the files
in our current folder. You can change
your default permission mode by editing
your settings in Cloud. You need to have
this part in your JSON. But it's not the
only way. You can start your CloudCode
with any permission you want with these
commands. But how does auto mode work? I
took this diagram from the official
video. So, let's say I started a new
Claude code session and I wrote my first
prompt and now Claude code wants to
execute its first action. An action can
be editing files, fetch websites, or
even executing bash commands. If we're
in auto mode, the first step is looking
in our rules. These rules lives in a
setting file that we're going to see in
a second. If there's an exact
instruction and Claude code knows how to
handle this action to deny or approve
it, you won't get into the classifier.
For example, I can config that Claude
code can fetch the web whatever it wants
and search any website it needs. But on
the other hand, it won't be able to
execute any git push command. Anthropic
described it perfectly in their video.
>> Use the environment field to describe
your infrastructure in plain English,
such as your GitHub org, cloud buckets,
and internal services. Setting
environment for places Claude's built-in
entries. So, add a default string to
keep them.
If you need more fine-grained control,
use allow for exceptions, soft deny for
actions that should be blocked unless we
explicitly ask, and hard deny for
actions that should be blocked no matter
what you ask. These fields are guidance
the classifier factors into each check,
not hard rules. For hard limits, add
deny rules to block matching tool calls,
and ask rules to force a prompt even in
auto mode. Allow rules also work, too.
>> If you want to see full tutorial on this
configuration file, tell me in the
comments. But if Claude doesn't know how
to handle this action after reading the
rules, it will go into the classifier. A
classifier is just an AI model.
According to these commands, it is just
Sonnet 5. This model lives in a separate
context and with every permission
request from Claude, it tries to answer
two questions. First, does this action
can lead to a security issue? And
second, does this action is dangerous
and irreversible? For example, deleting
the files in your folder. If both of the
answers are no, it will give permission
to Cloud Code to execute this action. If
one of them is yes, the request will be
denied. So, we understand the classifier
is a crucial part in auto mode, but is
the classifier's decision logged? Yes
and no, and I'll explain. You can track
these decisions by using the open
telemetry, but in order to do so, you
need to have the right background, and
it's almost impossible for the regular
Cloud Code user. So, practically, you
don't have an option to see the previous
decisions. Auto mode is great, but if
you want to take Cloud to the next
level, you must master Cloud skills.
Luckily, here are seven ways to do just
that.